

Muhammad Ahmad Waseem

Machine Learning Engineer – GitHub, Scholar, LinkedIN

ABOUT ME

As a Machine Learning Engineer with more than 3 years of expertise in Computer Vision and Deep Learning, I am passionate towards the development of Albased solutions for industries that will not only promote AI in the country but will also help me nourish my skills further.

SKILLS

- Python
- Data Analysis
- Troubleshooting
- Teamwork
- Communication

CONTACT

+92 321 4908 139

□ ahmadwaseem648@gmail.com

Lahore, Pakistan

WORK EXPERIENCE

CITY at LUMS | Aug 2021 - current

Team Lead - Tech Side

Tasks:

- Developed multiple Deep Learning and Computer Vision based solutions for the institute.
- Top solutions include Vehicle Detection and Classification, Image Segmentation for Building Detection, and Instance Segmentation for Parking Slots Detection.
- Coordination with the team as well as Government organizations for implementation of institute's solutions.

Information Technology University | Sep 2020 – July 2021

Graduate Student Fellow

Tasks:

- Experience related to Computer Vision and Implementation.
- Developed basic code blocks for the paper published in BMVC.
- Conducted research on best practices related to Fellow responsibilities and duties.

MikroStarTech Pvt. Ltd | March 2020 - August 2020

Embedded Systems Engineer

Tasks:

- Developed T30G: A gateway for smart Bluetooth devices.
- Efficient interfacing between multiple devices through UART, I2C \& SPI
- Handful experience of working in a private company.

LANGUAGES

Urdu: Native

English: Proficient Punjabi: Proficient

EDUCATION

2020-2022 | Lahore - Pakistan

Master of Science - Electrical Engineering

Information Technology University - CGPA: 3.79/4

2016-2020 | Lahore - Pakistan

B.S. Electrical Engineering

University of Engineering and Technology – **CGPA**: 3.52/4

Achievements

- Two published articles at ISPRS.
- Two published articles at IEEE GARSS.
- One article published at the British Machine Vision Conference.
- Our developed AI solution was successfully implemented by LWMC.